Venus, Serena and a plan for greatness.
King Richard is a drama, history film directed by Reinaldo Marcus Green.
The story of how Richard Williams served as a coach to his daughters Venus and Serena,
who will soon become two of the most legendary tennis players in history.
Richard Williams, played by Will Smith.
Oracene 'Brandy' Price, played by Aunjanue Ellis-Taylor.
Venus Williams, played by Saniyya Sidney.
Serena Williams, played by Demi Singleton.
Rick Macci, played by Jon Bernthal.
Tunde Price, played by Mikayla LaShae Bartholomew.
King Richard is a 2021 American biographical sports drama film directed
by Reinaldo Marcus Green and written by Zach Baylin.
The film stars Will Smith as Richard Williams, the father and coach of famed tennis players Venus and Serena Williams (both of whom served as
executive producers on the film), with Aunjanue Ellis, Saniyya Sidney, Demi Singleton, Tony Goldwyn, and Jon Bernthal in supporting roles.
It premiered at the 48th Telluride Film Festival on September 2, 2021, and was
theatrically released on November 19, 2021, by Warner Bros.
Pictures and on the HBO Max streaming service.
Although it was a box office failure, grossing $39 million against a budget of $50 million, the film received positive
reviews from critics, with praise for the screenplay and the performances of Smith, Ellis, and Sidney.
It was named one of the ten best films of the year by both the
American Film Institute and the National Board of Review.
It earned six nominations at the 94th Academy Awards, including
Best Picture, and won Best Actor for Will Smith.
The film explores themes of sports, tennis, tennis
player, father, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.